



- +1508 202 1641
- ✓ rauf.devs@gmail.com
- Pramingham, MA 01702
- http://abdur-work.github.io/

# **ABOUT ME**

I am a Senior PHP Developer with well over 10+ years of professional experience in developing web applications. I continue to grow and learn everyday. I have the ability to take on any size project or client and deliver a product or website that meets today's web standards and expectations.

### EDUCATION

### **BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE**

Framingham State University 2014 - 2016

# Abdur Rauf

### WEB DEVELOPER

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Web Developer at GrammercyTech

DEC 2017-Current

- Built in Laravel framework and employing different variants as well.
- Its an event management service which is completely customization per every client's request.
- Every event is assigned an unique sub domain hosting the interactive event's content including run of scheduled programs, daily agenda, attendee's groups and directory listing, various plugins for showcasing client's portfolio.
- It also has custom built video and chat platforms and analytic tools.
- The content is managed from backend dashboard and the system also has an iOS and Android app displaying the event website.
- I had the opportunity to develop various modules as well as work on the client side of things.

### Full Stack Developer at Apogee Invent

FEB 2012 - MAR 2017

- Its a client based product showcasing services.
- Developed and maintain Shopify Applications, and stores and taken part in development.
- The backend is in vanilla PHP and for the frontend different platforms like WordPress, AngularJs or VueJs.
- I developed the e-commerce module with different payment gateways with additional day to day tasks and client specific sites.
- So the idea is to have a product with minimal features which then on client's request, custom modules would be added in as per the requirements.





# **2** +1 508 202 1641

- rauf.devs@gmail.com
- **②** Framingham, MA 01702
- http://abdur-work.github.io/

# Abdur Rauf

WEB DEVELOPER

### SKILLS



Front-end Development



Website Design



Web Coding



Wireframe Creation

# EXPERTISE

# **PROGRAMMING**

- OOP
- Design Patterns.
- PHP, MVC.
- Web Services, API, WSDL, JSON, SOAP, REST, XML

# **FRAMEWORKS**

- Laravel
- Codelgniter, Yii
- Zend, Symphony
- AngularJS, VueJS
- WordPress, Shopify
- MERN, MEAN Stack

### **DATABASES**

- MySQL
- SQL
- MongoDB
- Redis
- Firebase

### **WEB RELATED**

- VueJS, Angular, React, jQuery, VanillaJS
- HTML5, CSS3, AJAX, Bootstrap
- AnimateJS, BounceJS

### **SERVER SOFTWARES**

- Linux (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS)
- LAMP, XAMPP, Apache, Nginx,
- Amazon AWS (S3, EC2, RDB, Route53)
- SSH, cPanel, FTP